<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Molecular Genetics of Human Cancer on Cancer Genetics</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Molecular Genetics of Human Cancer on Cancer Genetics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cancer signaling, tumor microenvironment, and immunotherapy</title>
      <link>/reading/11-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/reading/11-reading/</guid>
      <description> Required Dr. Kun Ping Lu’s readings:
 Zhou XZ and Lu KP (2016) The isomerase PIN1 controls numerous cancer-driving pathways and is a unique drug target
 Koikawa et al. (2016) Targeting Pin1 renders pancreatic cancer eradicable by synergizing with immunochemotherapy
  Complementary reading Action items Points of reflection </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cancer transcriptomics</title>
      <link>/reading/08-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/reading/08-reading/</guid>
      <description> Required Marcin Cieslik and Arul M. Chinnaiyan (2018) Cancer transcriptome profiling at the juncture of clinical translation
Tofigh et al. (2014) Prognostic ease and difficulty of invasive breast cancer
Complementary reading Action items Points of reflection </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Childhood ALL and quiz</title>
      <link>/reading/04-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/reading/04-reading/</guid>
      <description>Required Hunger SPH and Mulligan. CG Acute Lymphoblastic Leukemia in Children, New England Journal of Medicine, 2015
Brady SW et al. The genomic landscape of pediatric acute lymphoblastic leukemia. Nature Genetics, 2022
Action items  Remember that if you have difficulty accessing these articles, the course web page has advice to use the Western VPN.
 Be ready for the Quiz after the talk. It will be about 30 minutes in length and cover up to the end of Lecture 3 (however ever far I got).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colon Cancer, and the study of the origin of cancers</title>
      <link>/reading/05-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/reading/05-reading/</guid>
      <description>Required  Zeuner A, Todaro M, Stassi G, De Maria R (2014) Colorecatal cancer stem cells: from the crypt to the clinic. Cell Stem Cell
 Kuipers EJ et al. (2016) Colorectal cancer. Nat Rev Dis Primers.
  Complementary reading If you would like to better understand EMT, this is a good paper to read: Kalluri and Weinberg (2009) The basics of epithelial-mesenchymal transition. The Journal of Clinical Investigation</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drs. C. Schild-Poulter and L. Dagnino</title>
      <link>/video/10-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/video/10-video/</guid>
      <description>Lecture 10</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>E3 ligases s &amp; epidermal architecture, progenitors, mechanisms of UV-caused SCC</title>
      <link>/reading/10-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/reading/10-reading/</guid>
      <description>Required Dr. Caroline Schild-Poulter’s readings:
 Senft et al. (2017) Ubiquitin ligases in oncogenic transformation and cancer therapy
 Dale et al. (2021) Advancing targeted protein degradation for cancer therapy
  Dr. Lina Dagnino’s readings:
 McHugh et al. (2020) The identification of potential therapeutic targets for cutaneous squamous cell carcinoma
 Fania et al. (2021) Cutaneous Squamous Cell Carcinoma: From Pathophysiology to Novel Therapeutic Approaches
 Tang, Kinwah, Chan (2021) Incidence and mortality rates of keratinocyte carcinoma from 1998–2017: a population-based study of sex differences in Ontario, Canada</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hallmarks everywhere</title>
      <link>/reading/02-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/reading/02-reading/</guid>
      <description>Required  Hanahan and Weinberg (2011) The Hallmarks of Cancer: Next Generation. Cell  Recommended  Hanahan D, Coussens L (2012) Accessories to the Crime: Functions of Cells Recruited to the Tumor Microenvironment. Cancer Cell
 Angiogenesis
 Tissue Invasion
  Complementary D. Hanahan speaking about the hallmarks of cancer
DNA replication
Action points Consider the various points of reflection throughout the slides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hallmarks everywhere</title>
      <link>/reading/03-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/reading/03-reading/</guid>
      <description> Required  Hanahan (2022) Hallmarks of Cancer: New Dimensions. Cancer Discovery  Recommended  Talmadge JE and Fidler IJ (2010) The Biology of Cancer Metastasis: Historical Perspective..  Complementary reading Friedl et al. (2012) Classifying collective cancer cell invasion
Action items Points of reflection </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hallmarks I</title>
      <link>/video/02-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/video/02-video/</guid>
      <description>Lecture 2</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hallmarks I</title>
      <link>/video/03-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/video/03-video/</guid>
      <description>Lecture 3</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mutations and microenvironment in tumor initiation</title>
      <link>/reading/07-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/reading/07-reading/</guid>
      <description>Required These are the readings from Dr. Turley
 Bissel MJ, Ines WC (2011) Why don’t we get more cancer? A proposed role of the microenvironment in restraining cancer progression
 Martincorena I et al. (2015) High burden and pervasive positive selection of somatic mutations in normal human skin
 Tian X et al. (2013) High molecular weight hyaluronan mediates the cancer resistance of the naked mole-rat
  For the second hour, during my talk:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orientation and Introduction to Hallmarks</title>
      <link>/video/01-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/video/01-video/</guid>
      <description>Lecture 1</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orientation and the first 6 hallmarks</title>
      <link>/reading/01-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/reading/01-reading/</guid>
      <description>Readings should be completed before the actual lecture. The lecture itself is intended to provide a deeper exposition of the material and provide additional insight.
Required  Please read the Overview for the course and familiarize yourself with the content at OWL.1
 Please read the Resources for the course.
 The Hallmarks of Cancer Hanahan and Weinberg (2000) Cell. Volume 100, Issue 1.
 Consider the two textbooks The biology of cancer, 2nd edition from R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Role of the lung microenvironment in mediating breast cancer metastasis</title>
      <link>/reading/06-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/reading/06-reading/</guid>
      <description> Required  Peinado H et al. (2017) Pre-metastatic niches: organ-specific homes for metastases. Nature Reviews.
 Shani O et al. (2021) Evolution of fibroblasts in the lung metastatic microenvironment is driven by stage-specific transcriptional plasticity. eLife,
  Complementary reading Action items  Remember that if you have difficulty accessing these articles, the course web page has advice to use the Western VPN.  Points of reflection </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virus/host interactions &amp; sensitizing tumors for immunotherapy</title>
      <link>/reading/09-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/reading/09-reading/</guid>
      <description> Required Dr. Joe Mymryk’s readings:
 Zapatka et al. (2020) The landscape of viral associations in human cancers  Dr. Saman Malecki’s readings:
 Motta et al. (2021) Immunotherapy in microsatellite instability metastatic colorectal cancer: Current status and future perspectives
 Li et al. (2022) Gut microbiome in modulating immune checkpoint inhibitors
  Complementary reading Action items Points of reflection </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignment 1</title>
      <link>/assignment/01-assignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/assignment/01-assignment/</guid>
      <description>Google Drive Document</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignment 1</title>
      <link>/solutions/01-solutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/solutions/01-solutions/</guid>
      <description>here.
Solutions to Assignment 1</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignment 2</title>
      <link>/assignment/02-assignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/assignment/02-assignment/</guid>
      <description>Google Drive Document</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignment 2</title>
      <link>/solutions/02-solutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/solutions/02-solutions/</guid>
      <description>here.
Solutions to Assignment 2</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cancer transcriptomics</title>
      <link>/class/08-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/class/08-class/</guid>
      <description> Slides  Dr. Dumeaux  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Kun Ping Lu</title>
      <link>/class/11-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/class/11-class/</guid>
      <description> Slides  Dr. Kun Ping Lu  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modern bioinformatics tools for cancer</title>
      <link>/class/07-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/class/07-class/</guid>
      <description> Slides  Bioinformatics Resources
 Hallmarks III
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orientation and first hallmarks</title>
      <link>/class/01-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/class/01-class/</guid>
      <description> Slides  Orientation
 Hallmarks I
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orientation and first hallmarks</title>
      <link>/class/02-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/class/02-class/</guid>
      <description> Slides  Hallmarks II  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orientation and first hallmarks</title>
      <link>/class/03-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/class/03-class/</guid>
      <description> Slides  Hallmarks II
 Hallmarks III
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orientation and first hallmarks</title>
      <link>/class/example_01-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/class/example_01-class/</guid>
      <description> Slides  Orientation
 Hallmarks I
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quiz 1</title>
      <link>/solutions/01-quiz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/solutions/01-quiz/</guid>
      <description>Google Drive Document</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignments</title>
      <link>/assignments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/assignments/</guid>
      <description>Homework assignments 1
There are two assignments that are each worth \(15\%\). Generally, each assignment covers material we covered in class either through the required readings and lectures in class or from invited speakers. They are designed so that you can explore concepts and data in more depth.
Seeking assistance You should complete the assignments alone, however it is perfectly ok to ask for help. This order is the best for asking for assistance:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overview</title>
      <link>/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/</guid>
      <description>Course objectives 1 After some 45 years of research, we now understand how genes with specific mutations govern a wide range of traits of cancer cells. Some mutations in some genes initiate carcinoma while other mutations confer existing tumors with new capacities that help it thrive. Techniques to study the genetics of cancers have advanced tremendously over this period. In 1975 it was a major effort to sequence a single gene.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Contents  Project Proposal Full Project Some Suggestions   [^circos]
The project has two components. In the first part of the course, you are asked to submit a project proposal. This will detail the topic and scope of your project. There is great latitutde for choosing a specific topic; some examples are provided below to inspire your choice. The project proposal is worth \(5\%\) of your grade. The purpose of the project proposal is to get you thinking early about a topic that interests you so that you can add to your project as the semester progresses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resources/</guid>
      <description>Contents  Scientific literature Bioinformatic resources Time management Resource management Markdown Modern lab notebooks Citations and bibliography   Information technologies that may be useful for course work and research
Scientific literature  This Western Libraries’ Tutorials is a very nice series of videos for accessing different types of information.
 If you are trying to access journal articles from home (not within the UWO domain), this Western Library URL generator is probably what you need.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syllabus</title>
      <link>/syllabus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/syllabus/</guid>
      <description>Readings should be completed before each class session. Assignments can be found at at the Assignments page and at OWL. Assignment are submitted using OWL.
  Date Number Topic Reading Video Slides+ Assignment Solutions     Sept 13 Lecture 1, Hour 1  M. Hallett; Orientation        Sept 13 Lecture 1, Hour 2 M. Hallett; Sustained proliferative signalling and tumor suppressor genes        Sept 20 Lecture 2, Hour 1 M.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
