<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Readings on Cancer Genetics</title>
    <link>/reading/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Readings on Cancer Genetics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/reading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cancer transcriptomics</title>
      <link>/reading/08-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/reading/08-reading/</guid>
      <description> Required Marcin Cieslik and Arul M. Chinnaiyan (2018) Cancer transcriptome profiling at the juncture of clinical translation
Tofigh et al. (2014) Prognostic ease and difficulty of invasive breast cancer
Complementary reading Action items  Remember that if you have difficulty accessing these articles, the course web page has advice to use the Western VPN.  Points of reflection </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Childhood ALL and quiz</title>
      <link>/reading/04-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/reading/04-reading/</guid>
      <description>Required Hunger SPH and Mulligan. CG Acute Lymphoblastic Leukemia in Children, New England Journal of Medicine, 2015
Brady SW et al. The genomic landscape of pediatric acute lymphoblastic leukemia. Nature Genetics, 2022
Action items  Remember that if you have difficulty accessing these articles, the course web page has advice to use the Western VPN.
 Be ready for the Quiz after the talk. It will be about 30 minutes in length and cover up to the end of Lecture 3 (however ever far I got).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colon Cancer, and the study of the origin of cancers</title>
      <link>/reading/05-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/reading/05-reading/</guid>
      <description>Required  Zeuner A, Todaro M, Stassi G, De Maria R (2014) Colorecatal cancer stem cells: from the crypt to the clinic. Cell Stem Cell
 Kuipers EJ et al. (2016) Colorectal cancer. Nat Rev Dis Primers.
  Complementary reading If you would like to better understand EMT, this is a good paper to read: Kalluri and Weinberg (2009) The basics of epithelial-mesenchymal transition. The Journal of Clinical Investigation</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hallmarks everywhere</title>
      <link>/reading/02-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/reading/02-reading/</guid>
      <description>Required  Hanahan and Weinberg (2011) The Hallmarks of Cancer: Next Generation. Cell  Recommended  Hanahan D, Coussens L (2012) Accessories to the Crime: Functions of Cells Recruited to the Tumor Microenvironment. Cancer Cell
 Angiogenesis
 Tissue Invasion
  Complementary D. Hanahan speaking about the hallmarks of cancer
DNA replication
Action points Consider the various points of reflection throughout the slides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hallmarks everywhere</title>
      <link>/reading/03-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/reading/03-reading/</guid>
      <description> Required  Hanahan (2022) Hallmarks of Cancer: New Dimensions. Cancer Discovery  Recommended  Talmadge JE and Fidler IJ (2010) The Biology of Cancer Metastasis: Historical Perspective..  Complementary reading Friedl et al. (2012) Classifying collective cancer cell invasion
Action items Points of reflection </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mutations and microenvironment in tumor initiation</title>
      <link>/reading/07-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/reading/07-reading/</guid>
      <description>Required These are the readings from Dr. Turley
 Bissel MJ, Ines WC (2011) Why don’t we get more cancer? A proposed role of the microenvironment in restraining cancer progression
 Martincorena I et al. (2015) High burden and pervasive positive selection of somatic mutations in normal human skin
 Tian X et al. (2013) High molecular weight hyaluronan mediates the cancer resistance of the naked mole-rat
  For the second hour, during my talk:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orientation and the first 6 hallmarks</title>
      <link>/reading/01-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/reading/01-reading/</guid>
      <description>Readings should be completed before the actual lecture. The lecture itself is intended to provide a deeper exposition of the material and provide additional insight.
Required  Please read the Overview for the course and familiarize yourself with the content at OWL.1
 Please read the Resources for the course.
 The Hallmarks of Cancer Hanahan and Weinberg (2000) Cell. Volume 100, Issue 1.
 Consider the two textbooks The biology of cancer, 2nd edition from R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Role of the lung microenvironment in mediating breast cancer metastasis</title>
      <link>/reading/06-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/reading/06-reading/</guid>
      <description> Required  Peinado H et al. (2017) Pre-metastatic niches: organ-specific homes for metastases. Nature Reviews.
 Shani O et al. (2021) Evolution of fibroblasts in the lung metastatic microenvironment is driven by stage-specific transcriptional plasticity. eLife,
  Complementary reading Action items  Remember that if you have difficulty accessing these articles, the course web page has advice to use the Western VPN.  Points of reflection </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
